<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Development on Renganathan&#39;s Personal Website</title>
    <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/categories/web-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Development on Renganathan&#39;s Personal Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 10:01:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://renganathanr.github.io/categories/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week4-20200614</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 10:01:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes4/</guid>
      <description>In this week, I learned less amount of things related to web development. Last week I created a basic todo webapp in order to perform its primary purpose and found many unknown Flask syntaxes in it. So I learned those unknowns and debug my webapp.
Debugging 1. Identify and show a warning message if empty string entered into task content form In first when I created the app by following the Youtube tutorial - Learn Flask for Python - Full Tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week3-20200607</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 19:08:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes3/</guid>
      <description>This week I learned the basics of sqlite database with the help of a website named execute program and its link - Basic working with SQLite and simultaneously created a basic todo webapp using a Youtube tutorial - Learn Flask for Python - Full Tutorial.
SQLite learning process The website uses a good strategy (Spaced Repetition system) to teach the required content and only 16 lessons are free. So it takes the whole week to progress through the free lessons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week2-20200531</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 12:39:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes2/</guid>
      <description>In the previous week I learned the creation of a static site. This week I moved on and learned to make a dynamic website.
Goal The goal is to create a basic todo web application. For this, you need to have some basic understanding and knowledge of handling HTML and CSS, Python and its dependencies, Database application.
Status Right now, I learned how to use HTML without CSS to show some basic content in a browser with help of Python with one of its framework Flask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week1-20200524</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 09:58:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes1/</guid>
      <description>This is my first week I wrote week notes for my blog. In this week I learned so many information about creation of a web application.
First I learned that there exists two types of website. One is static site and another one is dynamic site. The difference is the contents in the static website are preloaded and only managed by client side whereas in the dynamic sites it can also done through the server side.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>