<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Renganathan&#39;s Personal Website</title>
    <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Renganathan&#39;s Personal Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 18:21:20 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://renganathanr.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week2-20200531</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 12:39:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes2/</guid>
      <description>As a continuity of first week, I get into learning of making a dynamic website.
Goal The goal is to create a basic todo web application. For this, you need to have some basic understanding and knowledge of handling HTML and CSS, Python and its dependencies, Database application.
Status Right now, I learned how to use HTML without CSS to show some basic content in a browser with help of Python with one of its dependency Flask.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 23:22:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/privacy/</guid>
      <description>  This is an open-source project created using Hugo and hosted by GitHub Pages.
  The credits for the images used in this site goes to http://pexels.com.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 22:52:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Renganathan, a graduate mechanical engineering student studying at Rochester Institute of Technology, New York, USA. I am from India. I love to live a natural life.
I learned this very lesson of sharing things with others all through my life.This blogging site is created in the aim of sharing the information which will be helpful for someone at some point. I am an amateur but interested in learning the computer science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week1-20200524</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 09:58:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/weeknotes1/</guid>
      <description>This is my first week I wrote week notes for my blog. In this week I learned so many information about creation of a web application.
First I learned that there exists two types of website. One is static site and another one is dynamic site. The difference is the contents in the static website are preloaded and only managed by client side whereas in the dynamic sites it can also done through the server side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 22:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Design of CVD end caps and membrane holder (Apr 2020)
An altered design for existing CVD endcaps to make it easier to use and a new concept design of membrane holder for nanobiotechnology applications were done using Fusion 360 on my independent study.
Design of a RC car (Apr 2020)
Design of a RC car was done using Fusion 360 for the 3D printing process to implement CAD knowledge and to learn the science and mechanical aspects behind different 3D printers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 22:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/resume/</guid>
      <description>Name: Renganathan Raja Chithambaram
Email: rr9641[at]rit[dot]edu
Blog: http://renganathanr.github.io
Github: https://github.com/renganathanr
Education:
* Master&#39;s in Mechanical Engineering - Rochester Institute of Technology (Expected graduation @ 2021) - CGPA (3.3/4)* Bachelor&#39;s in Mechanical Engineering - Anna University, India (2017) - CGPA (6.98/10) Knowledge &amp;amp; Skills:
* Computing knowlegde * Programming languages - Python (Novice)* General Softwares - Word processors, Spreadsheets, Presentations* Engineering softwares - Kiss soft, Pro-E/Creo, Fusion 360, MATLAB* Technical skills* 3D Printing, Computer harware diagnosis* Certification* Lean Six Sigma (Yellow belt) Work Experience:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SpringCourses</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/springcourses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 18:43:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/springcourses/</guid>
      <description>Courses taken in Spring semester=&amp;gt; CGPA: 3.3 1. Introduction to Optimal Design=&amp;gt; Grade: B+ In this coursework, I learned the optimization techniques which will help to achieve better results in some real world problems. For example, take a car. While thinking, the common design variables which meet customer expectations are fuel efficiency, lifetime, and safety. Specifically saying the break efficiency is a design variable that helps to achieve better fuel efficiency and safety of the car but there are some constraints like profit, loss, and environmental considerations that determine the line between customer satisfaction and sales of a company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MyFirstPost</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/myfirstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 21:50:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/2020/myfirstpost/</guid>
      <description>I was a normal person who actually browse through the web. Now, I started my own blogging site and gonna post my first post. This is interesting that you get something for your effort. I feel happy right now becuase of making this blogging site worked.
The purpose behind the site creation is to share the knowledge and to improve my English proficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>