<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Renganathan&#39;s Personal Website</title>
    <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Renganathan&#39;s Personal Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 18:43:37 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SpringCourses</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/springcourses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 18:43:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/springcourses/</guid>
      <description>Courses taken in Spring semester=&amp;gt; CGPA: 3.3 1. Introduction to Optimal Design=&amp;gt; Grade: B+ In this coursework, I learned the optimization techniques which will help to achieve better results in the real world problems. Techniques like Kuhn-Tucker method, Bisection method, Powell&amp;rsquo;s method, Cubic search method, Golden Section method, Steepest Descent method, Fletcher Reeves method, Davidson-Fletcher-Powell method, Broydon-Fletcher-Goldfarb-Shanno method, Newton&amp;rsquo;s method, Exterior Penalty Function method, Extended Interior Penalty Function method, Augmented Legrangian method, Sequential Linear Programming method, Method of Center, and Method of Feasible Directions are all learned through this coursework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebsiteInfo</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/websiteinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 14:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/websiteinfo/</guid>
      <description>Renganathan&amp;rsquo;s Personal Website The reason behind the creation of this site. I like a famous saying &amp;ldquo;Knowledge is the power&amp;quot;. Now we are all on Internet age. So with the help of current interface, I would like to share my knowledge to everybody.
I have a plan of making small scale applications using Python in the backend and Markdown in the frontend and I am using the Hugo, a static site generator for creating this website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MyFirstPost</title>
      <link>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/myfirstpost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 21:50:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://renganathanr.github.io/blog/myfirstpost/</guid>
      <description>About me I am Renganathan Raja Chithambaram, who is currently a graduate mechanical engineering student studying at Rochester Institute of Technology, New York.
Although I am a mechanical engineering student, I love computing. So, I created my first web application and posted about my details through my first post. I am gonna post more information on my upcoming posts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>